Guide to the Walt Whitman papers, 1841-1940, bulk 1841-1891 RL.01378
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1852-1898 and undated
  - Correspondence from or by Whitman, 1861-1892
    - Eldridge, C. W.: 1873 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Telegram announcing death of Mrs. Louisa Whitman; handwritten by telegraph agent.
    - Harper's Magazine: To Editor, 1873 Nov. 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Description from Frey: Autograph letter, "431 Stevens st. cor West Camden, N. Jersey. Nov. 2, 1873"; one page, signed.
    - Harper's Magazine: To Foreman in the Composing Room, 1873 Dec. 15 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Note requesting two proofs of "Prayer of Columbus" following corrections.
    - Johnson, R. U.: 1884 Aug. 4 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To R. U. Johnson, "328 Mickle street Camden New Jersey August 4 1884"; two pages, signed. Mounted with an autographed copy of the E. C. Stedman broadside, "Good-bye, Walt."
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1881 Dec. 21 (Box 7)
      Description from Frey: Letters and postcards from Whitman to W. S. Kennedy, 1881- 1889, mounted by Kennedy in three scrapbooks, which were later bound together in a single folio volume, 268 pages in all. The volume now contains fourteen autograph letters from Whitman, fourteen pages, dated as follows: "431 Stevens street Camden New Jersey Dec 21 '81"; "Camden, Aug 5 '86"; "Camden Feb. 21 '87 p m"; "Camden March 1 '87 2 1/2 p m"; "Camden Monday forenoon June 13 '87"; "Camden July 13, '87"; "328 MJckle street Camden New Jersey Sept: 14 '87"; "Camden Nov. 17 '87 noon"; "Camden Jan 10 '88"; "Camden Evn'g March 26 '88"; "Camden May 7 Evn'g '88"; "Camden Saturday night Sept: 1 '88"; "Camden Friday Evn'g Oct: 19 '88"; "Camden Saturday p m Jan: 5 '89." There are also seventy-seven autograph postcards and four autograph notes from Whitman to Kennedy, dates running from February 25, 1881 to May 8, 1889; thirteen copies by Kennedy of passages in letters from Whitman to him and other friends; ten scraps of Whitman manuscript; seventeen letters and pieces of manuscript written by other persons, among them W. D. O'Connor, Ernest Rhys, Sylvester Baxter, and H. S. Salt; a telegram from Traubel to Kennedy asking that he serve as pall-bearer at Whitman's funeral. The volume also contains sixty-six clippings, several of which are annotated by Whitman, and about twenty miscellaneous pieces, including proofs or offprints of several of Whitman's poems, the program for Whitman's Lincoln lecture in Philadelphia, April 15, 1886, and the preliminary circular of the Walt Whitman Society.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1886 Aug. 5 (Box 7)
      Description from Frey: Letters and postcards from Whitman to W. S. Kennedy, 1881-1889, mounted by Kennedy in three scrapbooks, which were later bound together in a single folio volume, 268 pages in all. The volume now contains fourteen autograph letters from Whitman, fourteen pages, dated as follows: "431 Stevens street Camden New Jersey Dec 21 '81"; "Camden, Aug 5 '86"; "Camden Feb. 21 '87 p m"; "Camden March 1 '87 2 1/2 p m"; "Camden Monday forenoon June 13 '87"; "Camden July 13, '87"; "328 MJckle street Camden New Jersey Sept: 14 '87"; "Camden Nov. 17 '87 noon"; "Camden Jan 10 '88"; "Camden Evn'g March 26 '88"; "Camden May 7 Evn'g '88"; "Camden Saturday night Sept: 1 '88"; "Camden Friday Evn'g Oct: 19 '88"; "Camden Saturday p m Jan: 5 '89." There are also seventy-seven autograph postcards and four autograph notes from Whitman to Kennedy, dates running from February 25, 1881 to May 8, 1889; thirteen copies by Kennedy of passages in letters from Whitman to him and other friends; ten scraps of Whitman manuscript; seventeen letters and pieces of manuscript written by other persons, among them W. D. O'Connor, Ernest Rhys, Sylvester Baxter, and H. S. Salt; a telegram from Traubel to Kennedy asking that he serve as pall-bearer at Whitman's funeral. The volume also contains sixty-six clippings, several of which are annotated by Whitman, and about twenty miscellaneous pieces, including proofs or offprints of several of Whitman's poems, the program for Whitman's Lincoln lecture in Philadelphia, April 15, 1886, and the preliminary circular of the Walt Whitman Society.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Feb. 21 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Mar. 1 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 June 13 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 July 13 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Sept. 14 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Oct. 4 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Description from Frey: Autograph letter, "Camden Tuesday p m"; one page, signed with initials. Kennedy has added the date "Oct. 4. '87" in brackets.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Nov. 17 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 January 10 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 Mar. 26 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 May 7 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 Sept. 1 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 Oct. 19 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1889 Jan. 5 (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1889 Feb. 14 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Description from Frey: Autograph postcard, "Camden Evn'g Feb: 14 '89"; signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1889 Oct. 13 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Description from Frey: Autograph postcard, "Camden Oct: 13 p m '89"; signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1889 Oct. 17 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Description from Frey: Autograph postcard, "Camden New Jersey Oct: 17, '89"; signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Jan. 27 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Description from Frey: Autograph letter, "Camden p m Jan 27 '90"; one page, signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Feb. 10 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Description from Frey: Autograph postcard, "Camden Feb: 10 '90"; signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Apr. 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Description from Frey: Autograph postcard, "Camden Evn'g April 1 '90"; signed with initials. With a photograph of Whitman, a ticket to his lecture on Abraham Lincoln, Madison Square Theatre, April 14, 1887, and a clipping from the Philadelphia Press, April 16, 1886, describing Whitman's presentation of the lecture at the Chestnut Street Opera House. In a board folder.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Apr. 11 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Description from Frey: Autograph postcard, "Camden Ev'g April 11 '90"; signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 June 18 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To William Sloane Kennedy, "Camden June 18 1890"; one page, signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Aug. 4 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To the same, "Camden p m [Au]g: 4 '90"; written on the inside of an envelope addressed to Whitman by Bucke, signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Dec. 29 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To the same, "Camden p m Dec: 29 '90"; one page, signed.
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1881-1889 (Box 7)
      Letters and postcards from Whitman to W. S. Kennedy, 1881-1889, mounted by Kennedy in three scrapbooks, which were later bound together in a single folio volume, 268 pages in all. The volume now contains fourteen autograph letters from Whitman, fourteen pages, dated as follows: "431 Stevens street Camden New Jersey Dec 21 '81"; "Camden, Aug 5 '86"; "Camden Feb. 21 '87 p m"; "Camden March 1 '87 iy2 p m"; "Camden Monday forenoon June 13 '87"; "Camden July 13 ,g7". «^2g MJckle street Camden New Jersey Sept: 14 '87"; "Camden Nov. 17 '87 noon"; "Camden Jan 10 '88"; "Camden Evn'g March 26 '88"; "Camden May 7 Evn'g '88"; "Camden Saturday night Sept: 1 '88"; "Camden Friday Evn'g Oct: 19 '88"; "Camden Saturday p m Jan: 5 '89." There are also seventy-seven autograph postcards and four autograph notes from Whitman to Kennedy, dates running from February 25, 1881 to .May 8, 1889; thirteen copies by Kennedy of passages in letters from Whitman to him and other friends; ten scraps of Whitman manuscript; seventeen letters and pieces of manuscript written by other persons, among them W. D. O'Connor, Ernest Rhys, Sylvester Baxter, and H. S. Salt; a telegram from Traubel to Kennedy asking that he serve as pall-bearer at Whitman's funeral. The volume also contains sixty-six clippings, several of which are annotated by Whitman, and about twenty miscellaneous pieces, including proofs or offprints of several of Whitman's poems, the program for Whitman's Lincoln lecture in Philadelphia, April 15, 1886, and the preliminary circular of the Walt Whitman Society.
    - "McGuire": 1872 May 2 (Box 15)
      Description from Frey: Autograph letter, "Washington, May 2, 1872"; two pages, signed. With an autograph manuscript, written in ink on one sheet of ruled paper, about 10 x 8 inches; fifteen lines in ink, a fair copy of a portion of a document relating to land ownership in Texas. Mounted in a paper leaflet, folio.
    - Nicholson, Tommy: 1880 Dec. 17 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Autograph letter. 431 Stevens Street, Camden, New Jersey, writes of living with his brother and sister-in-law, and of getting out on the river or to Philadelphia. Transcript available.
    - Nicholson, Tommy: 1881 Mar. 17 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Autograph letter, Camden, New Jersey, U. S. America, 17 March 1881, discusses his health and his current "loafing place." Typescript available.
    - Nicholson, Tommy: 1883 Sept. 5 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Autograph letter. Camden, New Jersey, U.S.A., 5 Sept. 1883. Discusses his current living situation. Typescript available.
    - O'Connor, William D.: 1868 Oct. 4 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      No place, 4 Oct [1868]. Letter written to friends in the Attorney General's office; with allusion to the Grant-Colfax campaign. Bound with typescript.
    - Rolleston, T. W. H.: 1880 Dec. 2
      Description from Frey: Autograph postcard, "431 Stevens Street Camden New Jersey U S America Dec: 2" [1880]; signed. Laid in Grashalme, Zurich, 1889.
    - Rosetti, William: 1886 May 30 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Facsimile of letter to Rossetti concerning the relief fund.
    - Russell, Dr. LeBaron [?]: 1864 Feb. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Washington D.C., February 1864. Three-page letter describing the situation in the Union field hospitals for the Army in Culpepper and Brandy Station. Transcript available.
    - Ryder, Jr., Anson: 1866 Dec. 14 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Autograph letter. Washington, D.C., 14 Dec. 1866, Whitman writes of his promotion and health and of friends they have in common.
    - Stansberry, William: 1874 May 20 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Description from Frey: Rough draft of a letter, "May 20, '74"; three pages. With four autograph letters to Whitman from William Stansberry, dated December 9, 1873, May 12 and June 28, 1874, and July 21, 1875, Howard Lake, Wright County, Minnesota; and one autograph letter to Whitman from Mrs. Stansberry, July 15, 1874; sixteen pages in all. In a board folder.
    - Stilwell, Julia Elizabeth: 1863 Oct. 21 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Description from Frey: Autograph letter, "Washington October 21 1863"; three pages, signed.
    - Stoddart, J. M.: 1890 Apr. 24 (Box 15)
      Description from Frey: Autograph letter, "328 Mickle street Camden New Jersey April 24 '90"; one page, signed. With envelope and a proof copy of "To the Sun-Set Breeze," signed by Whitman.
    - Swinton, John: 1865 Feb. 3 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Autograph letter. Washington [D.C.] 3 Feb. 1865, requesting Swinton to write to Lt. Gen. Grant for a special exchange on behalf of George Whitman, who was a prisoner.
    - Tilton, J. W.: 1889 Jan. 6 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To J. W. Tilton, "Camden New Jersey Jan: 6 '89"; one page, signed; with envelope.
    - Tottie, Oscar: July 26
      Description from Frey: Autograph postcard, "Camden New Jersey U S America July 26"; signed. Mounted inside the front cover of Leaves of Grass, Camden, New Jersey, 1876. See: http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002372020
    - Trowbridge, J. T. [?]: 1870 [?] Sept. 24 (Box 2)
      Autograph letter. Brooklyn, N.Y., 24 Sept. Whitman writes that he is electrotyping a new edition, and would like the name of a potential bookseller in Boston.
    - Trubner and Company: 1873 Dec. 21 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Autograph letter. 431 Stevens St., Camden, New Jersey, U. S. America. Requests a closing account for sales of Leaves of Grass, and payment due.
    - Trubner and Company: 1878 Oct. 1 [?] (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To foreign book-dealers (Triibner & Co.?), "431 Stevens Street Camden New Jersey U S America Oct 1 '78"; one page, signed.
    - Van Wyck, Samuel: 1879 May 28 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To Samuel Van Wyck, "1309 Fifth av: near 86th street May 28 '79"; one page, signed; with envelope.
    - Waters, George: 1878 Nov. 10 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To George Waters, "Camden New Jersey Nov 10 '78"; one page, signed.
    - Whitman, George: 1861 July 12 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Description from Frey: Autograph letter, "Brooklyn July 12th, 1861"; four pages, signed "Walt." In a board folder.
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1866 June 26 (Box 9)
      Description from Frey: A collection of fifteen autograph letters, signed "Walt," written to his mother from Washington, D. C.: "June 26, 1866," four pages; "March 19, 1867," three pages; "March 26, 1867," two pages; "April 16, 1867," four pages; "April 30, 1867," three pages; "June 6, 1868," four pages; "July 10, 1868," two pages, with envelope; "August 24, 1868," two pages; "August 30, 1868," four pages, with envelope; "Nov. 24, 1868," four pages; "Aug. 22," two pages, "1872" has been added in another hand; "Aug. 27," one page, "1872" has been added; "Oct. 15," two pages, "1872" has been added; "Nov. 14," two pages, "1872?" has been added; "Jan 17," two pages, "1868?" has been added [correct date is 1873]. In a red morocco folder.
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1866 June 29 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To Mrs. Louisa Whitman, "Attorney General's Office, Washington, Friday, June 29, 1866"; three pages, signed "Walt"; with envelope.
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1867 Mar. 19 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1867 Mar. 26 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1867 Apr. 16 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1867 Apr. 30 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 June 6 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 July 10 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 Aug. 24 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 Aug. 30 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 Nov. 24 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1872 Aug. 22 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1872 Aug. 27 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1872 Oct. 15 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1872 [?] Nov. 14 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1873 Jan. 17 (Box 9)
    - Whitman, Thomas Jefferson: 1867 Apr. 29 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Description from Frey: Autograph letter, "Attorney General's Office, Washington. April 29, 1867"; three pages, signed "Walt."
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1889 Dec. 31 (Box 9)
      Description from Frey: Five autograph letters, signed, written from Camden to Edward Wilkins of London, Ontario, Canada, dated as follows: "Dec: 31 '89," one page; "March 20 '90," one page, with envelope; "April 29 1890," one page; "Dec: 24 1890," one page, with envelope; "Sept: 30 '91," one page, with envelope. In a maroon cloth folding case.
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1890 Mar. 20 (Box 9)
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1890 Apr. 29 (Box 9)
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1890 Dec. 24 (Box 9)
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1891 Sept. 30 (Box 9)
    - Letters to Unidentified Recipients: 1889 Oct. 7 (Box 2)
      Autograph note. No salutation, Camden, New Jersey, 7 Oct 1889. Whitman writes a brief update regarding literary matters.
    - Letters to Unidentified Recipients: 1891 May 8 (Box 2)
      Description from Frey: To ----, "May 8 '91 328 Mickle st: Camden NJ"; a signed note, written on a small scrap of paper.
  - Scrapbook
    Contents, including letters, photographs, advertisements, and an etching, have been removed for preservation concerns. Materials are now available in Box 2.
    - Scrapbook (Box 2A)
- Writings, 1841-1891 and undated
  Consists of manuscript drafts and revisions of Whitman's poetry and prose as well as proofs and published versions of his work from his early career in journalism up through the end of his life. The Camden edition refers to The Complete Writings of Walt Whitman, "Camden Edition." Edited by Richard Maurice Bucke, Thomas B. Harned, and Horace L. Traubel; additional material contributed by Oscar Lovell Triggs. New York and London: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1902. (10 vols.). The inclusive edition refers to Leaves of Grass. "Inclusive Edition." Edited by Emory Holloway. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, Page and Company, 1927. Also noted is Walt Whitman's Diary in Canada. Edited by William Sloane Kennedy. Boston: Small, Maynard and Company, 1904.
  - Manuscript Poems, circa 1855-1882 and undated
    Manuscript drafts and revisions of poems appearing in successive editions of Leaves of Grass and poems not published during Whitman's lifetime or not intended for Leaves of Grass.
    - Leaves of Grass
      Manuscript fragments are labeled "draft portions" if they constitute early drafts or revisions of a poem appearing in any of the editions of Leaves of Grass published during Whitman's lifetime. Fragments are labeled "draft outlines" if Frey suggests that they represent "ideas" treated in Leaves of Grass. Listed alphabetically by title.
      - "A nation announcing itself" (Volume 14)
        Description from Frey: Autograph manuscript, written in pencil on one sheet of ruled paper, about 6x7 inches. Recto: eleven verses, slightly revised. Verso: "Asia"; about twenty-two lines. A draft of the opening passage of "By Blue Ontario's Shore," 1856 version; notes used in "Salut au Monde," especially sections 2 and 6 (Inclusive Edition, page 601).
      - "Carols closing Sixty -Nine" (Volume 20)
        Description from Frey: Autograph manuscript, written in ink and purple and blue pencil on both sides of a sheet of paper, about 10 x 7 inches; about sixty words. In a board folder. Whitman's suggestions for the title which eventually became "Sands at Seventy" appear on recto (Camden Edition, vii, 36); on verso is written the final selection.
      - "The Great Laws do not treasure chips, or stick for the odd cent" (Volume 9)
        Description from Frey: Autograph manuscript, written on one sheet of ruled paper, about 4x7 inches. Recto: a fair copy, in ink, of six verses. Verso: "the palms of the hands are cut by the turned in nails"; four verses, written and revised in pencil. Bound in a quarto volume, cloth, orange morocco back. A fragment, two verses of which appear, much altered, in "Who Learns My Lesson Complete?" (Camden Edition, iii, 264-265); with verses on the epileptic and the idiot brother, used in "Faces" (Inclusive Edition, page 692).
      - "Great are the myths. ... I too delight in them" (Volume 10)
        Description from Frey: Autograph manuscript, written in ink on one sheet of ruled paper, about 6x8 inches. Recto: eleven verses, revised in ink and pencil. Verso: "The true friends of the Sabbath, and of its purifying"; fifteen lines, slightly revised. Bound in a quarto volume, cloth, brown morocco back. An early version of the opening of "Great Are the Myths" (Camden Edition, iii, 265-266), and a prose fragment used in "Memorial in Behalf of a Freer Municipal Government, and Against Sunday Restrictions" (Camden Edition, vi, 108).
      - "You lusty and graceflu [sic] youth! you are great" (Volume 11)
        Description from Frey: Autograph manuscript, written in pencil on one sheet of ruled paper, about 4x6 inches. Recto: four verses, revised. Verso: "Are the prostitutes noth'g? Are the mockers of religion noth'g?"; nine lines, revised. Bound in a quarto volume, cloth, orange morocco back. An early version of a part of "Great Are the Myths," section 1 (Camden Edition, iii, 272); two brief, half-sketched ideas, the first of which was slightly altered for use in the 1855 version of "To Think of Time," section 8 (Camden Edition, iii, 272; vi, 109).
      - "And now I care not to walk the earth unless a comrade walk by my side" (Volume 195)
        Description from Frey: Autograph manuscript, written on one sheet of paper, about 6x4 inches. Recto: seven verses, in ink, slightly revised. Verso: "The States Prairies Prairie Psalms? (Psalms ? (Praise)"; a list, in pencil. Mounted and framed with a photograph. An early draft of a portion of "In Paths Untrodden" (Inclusive Edition, page 591), and a list of thirteen suggestions for titles of poems or groups of poems (Camden Edition, vii, 13).
      - "Contents" (Volume 19)
        Description from Frey: Autograph manuscript, written in ink on one side only of fifteen sheets of paper, about 8x5 inches. Bound in a small quarto volume, half undyed morocco. The Table of Contents of the 1881-1882 edition of Leaves of Grass, written by Whitman, with instructions to the printer. Inserted are a proof of the title-page of the same edition with the poet's corrections and a printed circular consisting of two pages of testimonials and press comment, followed by the table of contents of the volume.
      - Leaves of Grass, 1881 - 1882
        Description from Frey: Printer's copy for portions of the 1881-1882 edition of Leaves of Grass; autograph manuscript and printed pages, with numerous manuscript corrections, additions, and instructions to the printer. The pages are numbered in Whitman's hand: 2-18, 34-100, 101-123, 215-223, 228-237, 245-263, 264-268, 369-387, 388-438, 473-479, 480-493, 502-529. Twelve volumes, octavo, half and full morocco. These volumes contain copy for the following sections or poems: 1. Inscriptions (the poem "Thou, Reader" is in manuscript). 2. Song of Myself. 3. Children of Adam. 4. Song of the Exposition. 5. A Song for Occupations. 6. Birds of Passage. 7. A Broadway Pageant. 8. By Blue Ontario's Shore. 9. Autumn Rivulets (the first three stanzas of "As Consequent, Etc." and the entire poem "The Prairie States" are in manuscript). 10. To Think of Time. 11. Whispers of Heavenly Death. 12. From Noon to Starry Night (lacks: "Spirit That Form'd This Scene" and "A Clear Midnight"). Additional material has been inserted in the second volume, as follows: (1) The Hollyer engraving, inscribed by Whitman. (2) An autograph manuscript, written in pencil on one sheet of ruled paper, about 4x8 inches. Recto: "myself to celebrate"; nine verses, much revised. Verso: "I do not pretend [to] compose a grand opera"; thirteen lines, extensively revised. An early draft of the opening of "Song of Myself" (Inclusive Edition, pages 553-554) and a prose fragment in which Whitman discusses his poetic purpose (Camden Edition, vi, 43). (3) A review of Leaves of Grass, 1855, clipped from the National Intelligencer. (4) A lock of Whitman's hair, enclosed in a wrapper inscribed by R. M. Bucke. The text of "Song of the Exposition," clipped from the New York Evening Post, September 7, 1871, has been mounted in the fourth volume.
        - I. Inscriptions (Volume 208)
        - II. Song of Myself (Pages 1-23) (Volume 209)
        - III. Children of Adam (Volume 210)
        - IV. Song of the Exposition (Volume 211)
        - V. Song of the Redwood (Volume 212)
        - VI. A Song for Occupations (Volume 213)
        - VII. Birds of Passage (Volume 214)
        - VIII. Broadway Pageant (Volume 215)
        - IX. By Blue Ontario's Shore (Volume 216)
        - X. Autumn Rivulets (Pages 1-26) (Volume 217)
        - XI. To Think of Time (Volume 218)
        - XII. Whispers of Heavenly Death (Volume 219)
        - XIII. From Noon to Starry Night (Volume 220)
      - "THE Poem ( ? One grand, eclipsing poem Poem of Materials" (Volume 15)